<?xml version="1.0"?>

<tool name="Gene Graph Enrichment Analysis (GGEA)" id="ggea">
 <description>detection of enriched consistency between differential expression and network constraints in non-metabolic pathways.</description>
        <command interpreter="Rscript">ggea_galaxy.R $eset $pwys $fcmat $pmat $result</command>
        <inputs>
		<param format="rdata" name="eset" type="data" label="Expression set"/>
		<param format="zip" name="pwys" type="data" label="Zip archive of pathway files"/>		
		<param format="rdata" name="fcmat" type="data" label="Fold change permutation matrix"/>
                <param format="rdata" name="pmat" type="data" label="P-Value permutation matrix"/>
	</inputs>
        <outputs>
                <data format="html" name="result" type="data" label="GGEA result"/>
        </outputs>

	<help>
Gene Graph Enrichment Analysis (GGEA) is an advanced enrichment strategy that leaves the traditional gene set dogma by testing for consistency between gene expression and constraints that are imposed on the genes by pathways and regulatory networks, respectively. A pathway is henceforth called enriched if it exhibits a significant number of regulatory links between genes that are expressed according to the biochemical nature of these links. Applications on clinical datasets have shown that GGEA is able to confirm, support and enhance the confidence in gene set enrichment results yielding a better understanding of the regulatory process. In some cases, GGEA can even reject false positive enriched pathways of GSEA, i.e. high scoring gene sets, that are contrary expressed to the regulation constraints.      

**Inputs**

**Expression set**

* An RData file containing the gene expression set.

**Zip archive of pathway files**

* A zip compressed archive of pathway xml files in KGML format. The pathways are targeted for enrichment investigation.

**Fold change permutation matrix**

* A pre-computed RData object storing the fold changes for all permutations.

**P-Value permutation matrix**

* A pre-computed RData object storing the p-values for all permutations.

-----

**Outputs**

**GGEA result**

* The result table of the enrichment analysis showing singnificance of enrichment for each investigated pathway. 
	</help>
</tool>


