<?xml version="1.0"?>

<tool name="PathWave" id="pw">
 <description>discovering patterns of differentially regulated enzymes in metabolic pathways.</description>
        <command interpreter="Rscript">pathwave.R $eset $pwys $groupcol $alpha $perm $result</command>
        <inputs>
		<param format="rdata" name="eset" type="data" label="Expression set"/>
        	<param format="zip" name="pwys" type="data" label="Zip archive of pathway files"/>
		<param name="groupcol" size="10" type="text" value="" label="Group column"/>		
		<param name="alpha" size="10" type="text" value="0.05" label="Significance niveau"/>
		<param name="perm" size="10" type="text" value="10000" label="Number of permutations"/>
	</inputs>
        <outputs>
                <data format="html" name="result" type="data" label="PathWave result"/>
        </outputs>

	<help>
PathWave is a graph enrichment approach for metabolic pathways. In contrast to common set enrichment tests, it takes the network topology of the pathways into account by applying adjusted wavelet transforms on an elaborated and new 2D grid representation of curated pathway maps from KEGG. For further information see the original publication (Schramm et al., PathWave: discovering patterns of differentially regulated enzymes in metabolic pathways, Bioinformatics, Vol. 26 no. 9 2010).

**Inputs**

**Expression set**

* An RData file containing the gene expression set.

**Zip archive of pathway files**

* A zip compressed archive of pathway xml files in KGML format. The pathways are targeted for enrichment investigation.

**Group column**

* The name of the column in the pData slot of the probe expression set that stores the group assignment (f.e. affected vs. unaffected).

**Alpha**

* The p-value cutoff that is used for the PathWave run. Default is 0.05.

**Number of permutations**

* determines how often the samples are going to be permuted during the computation. Default is 10000.

-----

**Outputs**

**PathWave result**

* The result table of the enrichment analysis showing significance of enrichment for each investigated pathway. 
	</help>
</tool>


