<?xml version="1.0"?>

<tool name="Convert probe eset to gene eset" id="probeEset2geneEset">
 <description>by summarizing gene expression behavior over all corresponding probes</description>
        <command interpreter="Rscript">probeEset2geneEset.R $probe_eset $gene_eset $groupcol $adjmethod $distr $volc</command>
        <inputs>
        	<param format="rdata" name="probe_eset" type="data" label="Probe expression set"/>
		<param name="groupcol" size="10" type="text" value="" label="Group column"/>
		<param name="adjmethod" type="select" label="Multiple testing correction method">
		<option value="BH" selected="true">Benjamini-Hochberg 1995</option>
		<option value="bonferroni">Bonferroni</option>
		<option value="holm">Holm 1979</option>
		<option value="hochberg">Hochberg 1988</option>
		<option value="hommel">Hommel 1988</option>
		<option value="BY">Benjamini-Yekutieli 2001</option>
		</param>
	</inputs>
        <outputs>
                <data format="rdata" name="gene_eset" type="data" label="Gene expression set"/>
		<data format="jpg" name="distr" type="Image" label="P-Value distribution"/>
		<data format="jpg" name="volc" type="Image" label="Volcano plot"/>
        </outputs>

	<help>
Reads in expression data at probe (set) level and summarizes gene expression behavior by averaging over all spots that are annotated to a particular gene. A subsequent differential expression analysis at the gene level is automatically performed.

**Inputs**

**Probe expression set**

* An RData file containing the expression set for the probes. The fData slot of the expression set must contain an 'ENTREZ' column that lists for each spot a belonging gene ID.

**Group column**

* The name of the column in the pData slot of the probe expression set that stores the group assignment (f.e. affected vs. unaffected).

**Multiple testing correction method**

* bonferroni: traditional conservative adjusting of p-values
* holm: strong control of family wise error rate using Holm (1979)
* hochberg: strong control of family wise error rate using Hochberg (1988)
* hommel: strong control of family wise error rate using Hommel (1988)
* BH: control of the false discovery rate using Benjamini and Hochberg (1995)
* BY: control of the false discovery rate using Benjamini and Yekutieli (2001)

-----

**Outputs**

**Gene expression set**

* An RData object storing the expression set that has been converted to gene level.

**P-Value distribution**

* The histogram of differential expression gene p-values.

**Volcano plot**

* The characteristic plot that shows the relation of fold change and p-value

	</help>
</tool>


